<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
    Copyright (C) 2006-2007 the original author or authors.

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
-->

<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Javascript Maven 2 Tools</title>
        <author email="nicoals.deloof@gmail.com">Nicolas De Loof</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Introduction">
            <img src="images/javascript-maven-logo.png" align="right" vspace="4" hspace="4" clear="all"/>
            <p>
  Javascript has been considered for long time to be a hack language for web
  pages, with lack of object orientation and too lazy syntax. Recent explosion
  of ajax "web 2.0" rich internet application demonstrates that javascript is
  a mature platform, with powerfull libraries and talentuous developers.
            </p>

            <p>
  Java development uses tools like Ant and Maven to handle project lifecycle and
  integrate build, documentation and reporting tools. Javascript also has
  various tools, but no real consensus on how to manage a javascript project.
  In particular, javascript development as part of a JEE web application should
  integrate well with exiting java tools.
            </p>

      <p>
  The javascript maven project provides maven plugins and extensions dedicated to
  javascript development, either as standalone pure javascript librairies or as
  part of web application. Its goal is to promote best development practices with
  a standardized project organization, so that developers can be quickly productive
  on a project and take advantage of the best tools available for javascript development,
  documentation or quality assurance.
      </p>

            <subsection name="Guides">
                <ul>
                    <li><a href="guide-javascript-development.html">Developing javascript projects with Maven 2 </a>:
                        A guide to developing Javascript librairies with Maven 2 support.</li>

                    <li><a href="guide-webapp-development.html">Developing web appplication with javascript </a>:
                        A guide to enhance Java web application development based on existing maven tools
                        with Maven javascript support.</li>
                </ul>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Maven Components">
                <ul>
                    <li><a href="javascript-maven-plugin/index.html">JavaScript Maven Plugin</a>:
                        Provides support for packaging, testing and other facets of JavaScript development.</li>

                    <li><a href="javascript-report-maven-plugin/index.html">JavaScript Report Maven Plugin</a>:
                        Reporting plugin for javascript documentation and quality assurance tools.</li>

                    <li><a href="javascript-maven-extension/index.html">JavaScript Maven Extensions</a>:
                        A set of maven extension to support Javascript development lifecycle.</li>

                    <li><a href="javascript-maven-archive/index.html">JavaScript Maven Archive</a>:
                        A set of maven components to support Javascript archives.</li>

                </ul>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
